Shoaib Meghani

Senior Mobile Engineer

meghani.shoaib@gmail.com +973 3341 2905

Skype: meghani.shoaib

LinkedIn: https://bh.linkedin.com/in/shoaibmeghani

Summary

A Tech enthusiast having 4 years of extensive experience in developing top notch mobile applications for Govt. Authorities, Official Sports Organizations, Universities, Banks, Standalone Products & Retail industry.

- Skilled at operating in a wide range of platforms with strong Object-Oriented Design and Analysis.
- Successfully worked in various capacities: Developer, Business analyst and Technical lead.
- Experienced in client coordination, facilitating clients in complete project life cycle from kick-off to closure.
- Developed apps for Dubai Smart Govt. and UAE authorities
- Received quarterly and yearly best performance awards

Skills

Mobility Android, iOS (integration with various 3rd party libraries/frameworks)

Front End JavaScript, HTML, Angular JS, Typescript

Database SQL, SQLite, ORMs (ORMLite, Sugar ORM, Core-data etc.)

Programming Java, Objective-C, C#

API Integration JSON, XML, SOAP, REST

Source Control *SVN, TFS, GitHub*

Agile Tools MS Project Plan, Balsamiq (Wireframing), MS Office

Experience

Mobile Developer at Veripark Gulf

October 2015 – Present (7 Months)

- Worked on Multi Channel Retail Internet Banking Solution by Veripark (VB 5.0)
- System Analysis
- Development / Code Review
- Change Request Management & Estimation
- Production Support / Debugging

Senior Software Engineer at Systems Ltd

February 2014 – October 2015 (1.9 years)

- Working in various capacities: Developer, Analyst, and Mentor.
- Designing frameworks and design patterns to meet complex client requirements.
- Involved in finalizing technical requirements and writing technical proposals.
- Responsible for providing supervision on-site and off-site
- Received quarterly and yearly best performance awards

Software Engineer at Duleaf FZE

June 2013 – February 2014 (9 months)

- Working on enterprise level apps.
- Leading and providing technical assistance to junior android engineers.
- Designing frameworks and design patterns to meet complex client requirements.
- Involved in entire project life cycle, from project kick off brainstorming to its delivery.

Android Freelancer

August 2012 - 2014 (2 years)

Education

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science, 2009 - 2013

Shaheed Zulfikar Ali Bhutto Institute of Science and Technology CGPA 3.3

Intermediate (Pre-Engineering), 2007 – 2009

Aga Khan Higher Secondary School, Karachi

Portfolio

Worked for renowned customers and delivered great projects. Following are some of the highlights:

Meem - Gulf International Bank Official App

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.veripark.GIB

mPay - Dubai Smart Govt App

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.duleaf.mpay

UAEFA – UAE Football Association official app

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.uaefa.android.app

F3 Championships – Hamdan Heritage Center official app

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ae.gov.hhc.android

GOYS - General Organization for Youth and Sports (Govt. Of Bahrain) official app

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.goys.android.app

SDTPS - Sharjah Directorate of Town Planning and Survey official app

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tawasol.Sharka

AMAF – Awqaf and Minors Affairs Foundation (Govt. of Dubai)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ae.gov.amaf.android

ADU - Abu Dhabi University Official App

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adu.an

OneLoad - Product by Systems Ltd

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.systems.oneload.android.app

Clever Im Netz – Parent Control app (Germany)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.axxessio.clever.im.netz